PORTFOLIO

iunh4533.qithub.io

SKILLS

Coding

HTML CSS Sass Redux
React JavaScript (ES6)
Python Django Bootstrap

SQL Node.js PHP

Software

Visual Studio Code

WordPress LocalWP XAMPP

MySQL Workbench Firebase

Trello Git GitHub Gitlab

Bubble Figma Dell KACE

EC2 S3 Lambda

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Cloud Practitioner

LANGUAGES

Fluent Chinese (Cantonese)
Proficient Chinese (Mandarin)
Intermediate Spanish

HOBBIES

Table Tennis Tennis
Scootering Travelling
Biking Paintball
Aspiring wingsuit flyer

CONTACT

P: +1 (347) 295 8842 E: junh4533@gmail.com

A: Brooklyn, NY 11220

LINKS

- in <u>linkedin.com/in/jun-huang1</u>
- github.com/junh4533
- devpost.com/junhuana

JUN HUANG

ABOUT

I am a NYC-based full-stack developer with 3 years of experience in UI/UX prototyping and web app development. I developed applications with MERN, Python-Django, WordPress, and Electron. My goal is to simplify our daily lives through coding practical and intuitive business solutions.

EDUCATION

MACAULAY HONORS AT CUNY BARUCH COLLEGE - BACHELOR OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

- Major: Computer Information Systems I Minor: NYC Studies with honors
- Graduated May 2021, Magna Cum Laude | GPA 3.8/4.0

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING FELLOW

U.S. Census Bureau - Remote I June 2021 - Present

- Use **Figma** to redesign the UI of the Demographic Analysis & Population Projection System (DAPPS), a .NET app designed to help international demographers conduct population research. Then used the Figma prototype to develop a UI library.
- Rebuild DAPPS using **HTML**, **CSS**, and **JavaScript** as the front-end and **Electron.js**, **Node.js**, and **R** as the back-end. DAPPS is packaged and deployed as a MacOS/Windows executable.
- Developed a data entry tool that parses Excel tables into **JSON**. a module for passing data from Node.js to R. and a projection/data visualization tool using **Chart.js**.
- Conduct bi-weekly sprints and daily standups. Use Gitlab to update the user stories and sprint backlog.

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Matchraiser.org - New York, NY I September 2020 - Present

- Develop interactive **React** components and pages for our donation platform: <u>matchraiser.org</u>. Created the landing page, FAQ page, navigation bar, footer, and various front-end components.
- Implement user stories in a SCRUM environment. Coordinate with the CEO/lead UI designer to ensure consistent designs.
- Design and implmement UI animations into our client interface.

WEB DEVELOPER

Baruch College - New York, NY | April 2018 - March 2020

- Developed web apps that automated file transfers, asset reporting, ticket reporting, and tech support queueing.
- Redesigned the client, staff, and admin interface of Baruch's queue management system that serves **250+ users weekly** (using **HTML**, **Sass**, **JS**, **Bootstrap**, and **React**).
- Developed a CRUD video streaming software using Python-Django that streams promotional videos across Baruch TVs.
- Utilized the WAMP stack (Windows, Apache, MySQL, PHP) to dynamically generate desktop backgrounds to 700+ PCs.

PROJECTS

SKILL.LY I FIGMA PROTOTYPE

• 1st Place project for the 2021 CUNY Hackathon. Used Figma to prototype an employment platform where applicants can certify their skills through company designed projects. Recruiters can then reach out to prospective employees: Figma url.

BARUCH QUEUEING SYSTEM I REACT APP

• Redesigned the UI of Baruch's support queuing system using **React**, **HTML**, **Sass**, and **Bootstrap**. When a user checks in, a POST request is sent to the **Dell KACE API** to create the ticket. Users are notified with the **Twilio API** when it is their turn.

ENROLLA I REACT APP

- Developed a class schedule generator that recommends classes based on a student's major and graduation requirement.
- Utilized HTML, Sass, JS, and Bootstrap to build the frontend. Backend was implemented with MySQL, Node, and Express,

LEADERSHIP & ACTIVITIES

LEAD FRONT-END DEVELOPER

SavingTakeouts - New York, NY | May 2020 - September 2020

- Co-founded a non-profit to connect top talent with small businesses to provide free web development and marketing services during the pandemic.
- Trained 3 developers to prototype WP themes with Figma. Used PHP filters and Ajax to customize theme functionality.
- Optimized the development process by developing a barebone WP template with Sass and LocalWP.
- Operated as a liaison between clients and developers by translating client needs into technical specifications.

VP OF TECHNOLOGY

Ascend - Baruch Chapter | June 2019 - June 2020

- Spearheaded an 8-week **HTML/CSS** and a 10-week **Python** workshop to introduce students to programming. Attracted over **80 applicants** and successfully converted our members into our talent pipeline.
- Streamlined the e-board's workflow and communication through integrating software like Trello, Slack, and G-Suite.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 2021 Ascend Hackathon: Revive Small Businesses (Team Etit) 2nd Place | March 2021
- 5th Annual CUNY Hackathon (Team Skill.ly) 1st Place, Most Creative Project, Best Wildcard Project | January 2021
- Santander Universities Entrepreneurship Scholarship I August 2020
- University Scholar (**4-year tuition** to Macaulay Honors College) I September 2017 May 2021